<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on morganwebdev&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on morganwebdev&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Morgan Murrah</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 08:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://morganwebdev.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Retooling</title>
      <link>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/retooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/retooling/</guid>
      <description>I have some time to retool and reconfigure my knowledge before being available to work again in December of this year. I have a list and order in which I plan to consult these amazing resources about programming. I have over five years of experience but there is a lot of low hanging fruit to gain by starting from some fundamentals:
10/19: Goals  Learn JavaScript in y Minutes  Completed reviewing this   JavaScript Garden  Currently part way through   Learn JavaScript Online course  Completed initial chapters   Eloquent JavaScript  I plan to complete the entire book, it has been reccomended many times!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments with Congress.gov API</title>
      <link>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/congress-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/congress-api/</guid>
      <description>This September Congress.gov released a neat new API!
 Congress.gov shares its application programming interface (API) with the public to ingest the Congressional data. Sign up for an API key from api.data.gov that you can use to access web services provided by Congress.gov. To learn more, view our GitHub page.
 It is possible to experiment with the API by signing up and then entering the key in the authorization dialog at the top of the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playwright: My intro</title>
      <link>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/playwright/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/playwright/</guid>
      <description>I am enamored with Playwright. End to end integration testing is a huge topic but I can tell you just a few things about my experience from helping to integrate JavaScript E2E tests at work and in my spare time projects:
First, I have to say I am sure I would have been enamored with experiencing the joy and utility of E2E testing with other frameworks as well including Cypress or TestCafe but Playwright is my first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paring down with AMP</title>
      <link>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/paring-down-with-amp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/paring-down-with-amp/</guid>
      <description>morganwebdev.com This is a post about my experience of simplifying my personal website down to an AMP page. My philosophy was incremental improvement using the validator and lighthouse test audits as guides. Additionally I added basic service worker functionality with the amp-install-serviceworker tag.
The result is an excellent lighthouse score and a pretty excellent WebPageTest score on Core Web Vitals:
I followed a number of steps to achieve this namely size bounding and inlining CSS and using the excellent Super Tiny Icons Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paring down with Parcel.js</title>
      <link>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/paring-down-with-parcel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/paring-down-with-parcel/</guid>
      <description>This is a small blog about how I pared down my personal website to a single page of HTML bundled with parcel.js. This was a change from a PWA Vue-CLI generated site using Webpack. I write this to express my appreciation of making maintenance easy and simplicity where possible.
Link to the Repository
What I want out of a personal website or &amp;lsquo;my personal bag of hyperlinks&amp;rsquo;. I want people to be able to click and find almost my entire web presence linked from one place on mobile or desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Mentoring</title>
      <link>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/github-mentoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/github-mentoring/</guid>
      <description>Over the course of 2020 and 2021 thus far I have mentored seven up and coming software developers from several communities: Bellingham Codes, Tech404 and Linkedin. I mentored them to optimize their GitHub account for prospective employers/recruiters/OSS opportunities. I spent 20-40mins over Zoom with each of them and learned a lot myself about what it is like getting started in the industry today. As of writing this, I am aware that one person has landed a job and one has advanced in interview stages aided by their GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020</title>
      <link>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/2020/</guid>
      <description>TLDR; I survived 2020 and managed a few wins What a year. What an incredible, awful, moving, emotional, massive year just to name a few adjectives.
I have had a lot of time on the computer this year. I have put in a lot of work as a distraction. Despite everything I managed a few wins this year. I figure I would focus on them to celebrate a little in general and celebrate this blog and the topics I may explore in the posts to come:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello to this Blog</title>
      <link>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/hello-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 17:14:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://morganwebdev.org/posts/hello-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to my new blog Hello. This is the first blog post on my deceptively simple new Hugo blog. I am using the Cactus Theme on Github with just a few modifications.
I really like a bunch of things about Hugo. Notably I was able to get started insanely fast without feeling like I was downloading a mountain of dependencies with NPM like when I tried (successfully, after much tooling around) to set up a blog with Gatsby.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
